searchsystems.net 2010-06-26

# Privacy Policy | SearchSystems.net

### Introduction

As a result of our unique position as the premier collection of public records databases on the Internet, SearchSytems.net is highly sensitive to the privacy concerns of our users, and therefore strongly committed to protecting our users' privacy every step of the way. As part of that commitment, we have outlined in detail what information will be collected, what measures are in place to protect that information, how that information will be used, with whom that information may be shared and on what basis that sharing will take place. And we assure you, the user, that we will at all times abide by the terms of this Privacy Policy and honor the trust that you have invested in us. If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please [contact us](http://premium.searchsystems.net/contact.php) via our online form; we will do our best to address your query in a timely and professional manner.

### Security

SearchSystems.net is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on limited access computer systems which are protected by firewalls and located within controlled facilities. Access to your personal information is limited to specific corporate employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs. When those employees leave the SearchSystems.net family, their old passwords are revoked on an immediate basis. When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a credit card number) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol, and through the use of our login system.

### Legal Compliance

SearchSystems.net shares information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of SearchSystems.net's terms of service, or as otherwise required by law. Personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, SearchSystems.net will notify our newsletter subscribers about the change, in addition to following the procedure outlined above. SearchSystems.net encourages you to periodically review this Policy to be informed of how we are protecting your information.

### Links

Links published on SearchSystems.net directing the user to Websites containing public record databases, or to Websites of strategic partners do not contain tracking technologies other than tracking clickthrough traffic. Please be aware that SearchSystems.net is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites, and that no representations are made as to personally identifiable information gathered by those Websites themselves. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Website.

### Children

Children are not eligible to use our newsletter and we ask that minors (under the age of 18) do not submit any personal information to us. SearchSystems.net does not knowingly sell to anyone under the age of 18.

### Information Collection

The level of personally identifiable information collected by SearchSystems.net directly corresponds with the user's level of usage, as follows:

  * Basic Users
  * Newsletter Subscribers
  * Partner Websites
  * eCommerce Services

> ### Basic Users
> 
> SearchSystems.net utilizes traffic statistics as a tool to optimize our site's usefulness to our users. For this reason, as well as for security purposes (e.g., logging hack attacks), SearchSystems.net collects I.P. Addresses (the equivalent of Internet "mailing addresses"; they tell other computers on the Internet where to send the information you have requested, such as new web pages or images. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information) browser type, domain names, access times, referring URL, and page view information of users who browse all areas of our Website. Individual information will not be shared with third parties, but aggregate site statistics may be shared for evaluation purposes.
> 
> ### Newsletter Subscribers
> 
> On a semi-regular basis (currently about twice annually), SearchSystems.net publishes an e-mail newsletter that tells all about our latest developments. If you decide to sign up for our newsletter at [http://searchsystems.net/signup.php](http://www.searchsystems.net/signup.php), we will collect the e-mail to which that subscriber's newsletter should be sent. Our sole purpose in collecting this information is so that we know who we are serving and where to send the newsletter; this information is not at any time linked to other personally identifiable information, nor is this data shared with third parties. When you sign up for the newsletter, an e-mail will be sent to the provided address confirming your subscription and containing unsubscribe instructions.
> 
> ### Partner Websites
> 
> In addition to strategic partnerships through which we offer premium services, SearchSystems.net also has entered into agreements with Partner Websites that allow our users to access the records provided by those Websites at an often-discounted rate. In such cases, as with Lexis-Nexis or Ancestry.com, SearchSystems.net does not actually collect any billing or credit card information, but merely records the referral to their site pursuant to our agreement with them, through the use of special URL's or co-branded pages. Once you leave SearchSystems.net and enter a Partner Website to subscribe for those services or merely to view their site, even where their site is co-branded with the SearchSystems.net logo, you are no longer on SearchSystems.net and therefore no longer covered by this Policy. Please peruse our Partner Websites' privacy policies prior to utilizing their services.
> 
> ### eCommerce Services
> 
> The only databases to which SearchSystems.net directly sells access to are our fee-based criminal and nationwide sex offender records found at https://premium.searchsystems.net. The pages that contain these services have a uniquely identifiable logo & design and are accessible to registered users only. Individuals who wish to register for these services must provide their credit card information and other personal data required to verify the authenticity of the transaction. This credit card and other personal information will not be divulged to anybody outside of those individuals or institutions that must have that data in order to complete the transaction. This bears repetition: your credit card and other personal information provided to SearchSystems.net in order to obtain access to our fee-based records will not be utilized for any purpose, or divulged to any person or entity, unless that use or disclosure is necessary in order to effectuate the transaction that you submitted it for.
> 
> Additionally, any such information provided will be maintained on a secure server at a locked facility where access is controlled by installed Biometric Palm Scanners and Card Key access controllers. SearchSystems.net takes the responsibility to guard your personal information very seriously, and we will take all reasonable measures to guard against its theft or improper disclosure.

### Choice/Opt-out

Our users are given the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site, at the point where we ask for the information. For example, users who no longer wish to receive our e-mail newsletters may opt-out of receiving these communications by following the unsubscribe directions in the newsletter or by [contacting us](http://premium.searchsystems.net/contact.php).

### Notification of Changes

SearchSystems.net will occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect company and customer feedback. You will be notified of any changes in our Privacy Policy by a link to the updated policy on the home page, including an icon indicating that the policy has recently changed. It is our commitment that our users will always be aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If, at any point, we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, SearchSystems.net will notify our newsletter subscribers about the change, in addition to following the procedure outlined above. SearchSystems.net encourages you to periodically review this Policy to be informed of how we are protecting your information.
